<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="https://ammyblabla.github.io/microsoftGitHub/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://ammyblabla.github.io/microsoftGitHub/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://ammyblabla.github.io/microsoftGitHub/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-07-19T17:29:14+09:00</updated><id>https://ammyblabla.github.io/microsoftGitHub/</id><title type="html">Impact of Microsoft Acquisition of GitHub</title><subtitle>Jekyll version of the Massively theme by HTML5UP</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Result from Google form (Part 1)</title><link href="https://ammyblabla.github.io/microsoftGitHub/blog/result-google-form-01/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Result from Google form (Part 1)" /><published>2018-07-17T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-07-17T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://ammyblabla.github.io/microsoftGitHub/blog/result-google-form-01</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ammyblabla.github.io/microsoftGitHub/blog/result-google-form-01/">&lt;script src=&quot;https://ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/libs/jquery/3.3.1/jquery.min.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://code.highcharts.com/highcharts.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://code.highcharts.com/modules/exporting.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://code.highcharts.com/modules/export-data.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;/assets/css/table.css&quot; /&gt;

&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;/assets/css/chart.css&quot; /&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;content&quot;&gt;   
  &lt;h2&gt;1. Which of the roles best describe your main activities within the Linux (distribution or kernel) or BSD?&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;chart&quot; id=&quot;1-1&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This question is the checkbox ,so participants can answer more than one choice. As a chart, most of participant is casual developers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;spacer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;2. Are you the fan of GitHub?&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;chart&quot; id=&quot;1-2&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Even though Microsoft acquire GitHub and Ballmer , Microsoft's ex-CEO, told &quot;Linux is a cancer&quot;. Most of participant still is GitHub fans.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;spacer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;2. Which do you think the acquisition will be beneficial or detrimental to any of the projects that you contribute torwards?&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;chart&quot; id=&quot;2-1&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;spacer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;chart&quot; id=&quot;2-2&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;spacer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;chart&quot; id=&quot;2-4&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;spacer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div id=&quot;table-scroll&quot; class=&quot;6-1&quot;&gt;
    &lt;table&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Moved to Gitea long before MS acquired GitHub&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;I still don't know exactly why Microsoft bought out GitHub, but they need to proceed very very carefully.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;For now, unless many other projects move fast (see last comment), I would stay with GitHub, but I am afraid of slowly typical Microsoft integrations, OneDrive, Skype, merge of GitHub and Microsoft account and such things. Would not surprise me but kills the whole idea of FOSS. I think the main reason why great open source related project fail, after big companies buy then, is that a large commercial company, which earn money the opposite way than FOSS related projects try, lack the needed feeling and motivation and relationship to/with the community to be able to bring it forward the right way. FOSS proprietary for me is simply an opposite approach. This of course cannot be tied to single people within e.g. Microsoft, but I think the company as a whole will slowly change GitHub in a way, that drives FOSS developers away, just because the idea of what is good and beneficial is simply a different one.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;It would be a good idea to have a similar survey regarding &quot;normal&quot; open-source projects hosted on GitHub.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;GitHub hurts open development by providing nonfree issue tracking, and rate limiting API access to those features therefore incurring vendor lock-in. To contribute to a GitHub project the contributors are forced to make a GitHub account and have to agree to a GitHub TOS rather than just the project's. I feel the situation will only get worse regarding terms issues with Microsoft management and usability wise the platform will further degrade judging by what happened to past Microsoft acquisitions such as Skype or Mojang.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;I feel that Microsoft did a good move and I hope it's a good news for the Open Source ecosystem&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;So Linux Torvalds the father of linux sold out to Microsoft, and practically works for RedHat exclusively ... I am expecting Microsoft to get control of RedHat and linux kernel development ... in other words Microsoft will end up owning linux. Then, there will only be MAC osx to turn too ... for the time being.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Think like this: &lt;br /&gt;
      1. Millions of people offers they labors for free, the hosting of this labor have sale it for a big amount of money to a company. Where's suppose to go the benefit ?&lt;br /&gt;
      2. What is going to be the benefit of Microsoft in spending such a lot of money for such a platform containing millions of projects that should at the end stays available for free.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;I feel sad about that notice&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;There's a Debian Debconf talk about being able to save / export comments an improved github alike platform. This would ease migrating from github to other platforms if it got implemented as an standard.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Microsoft is like a turd that just wont flush. It seems like they're on the most subtle embrace, extend, extinguish plan after fading to irrelevance. It seems that most are either unaware of Microsofts antics from the past or just fickle about it (ooh freebies) which is sad. I hope Microsoft would just die and go away.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Please consider adding &quot;Do you know the event ?&quot; as a question, because I don't. And that may affect the survey results.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;git is git. The git SaaS mostly doesn't matter. &lt;br /&gt;
      Also, now &quot;Microsoft has ALL the code&quot;. This includes github's commercial clients. This is similar to Amazon having most of the world's server code.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Microsoft does not abide by GNU/Linux philosophies, while Github is heavily intertwined with GNU/Linux philosophies.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;I am leaving github because of Microsoft's history of intentionally squashing competing technologies. I cannot support unethical companies.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;I've seen a few of the open source hardliner projects move away from GitHub or issues opened on projects that they should move away from GitHub.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;I don't see anything wrong with buying Github by Microsoft. For example, we use Skype so far and we will continue to use it until it suits our needs, or until we do something relatively convenient for us.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Today we need more than ever FREEDOM. We can have in a commercial world, we have had in the past in the USA, not in the URSS! But we need to know and understand and defend freedom.&amp;lt;&lt;br /&gt;Today and not since today our freedom is getting smaller and smaller from the hardware (UEFI (in)secure-boot etc) to services (how many people instead of have a local maildir sync-ed, for instance, only live on webmails?) to the society in general.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;the &quot;Which statement best describes your current situation with any of your contributed projects?&quot; question did not provide for my answer - the project I use most is not on Github, but others I do activity work on are on github and have not moved away&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;I think the main avantage of gihub is the size of the account pools so it lowers small contribution by lot of people because they have previously an account. It will not be lost by the acquisition.&lt;br /&gt;In my opinion, the goal of microsoft is to provide an automatic deployment to azure. So it's more a bad news to proprietary service like heroku.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;it would be great when you release the results as open data for the research community to work with&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;I could not answer question &quot;Which statement best describes your current situation with any of your contributed projects?&quot; as my answer would be: The projects that I contribute to the most is currently not using GitHub, some projects that I contribute to use GitHub.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;monopoly&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;GitHub is not the &quot;silver bullet&quot;: some of the most successful projects in the world don't even use GitHub - or never used. That said, it's very sad for the OSS community that a company like Microsoft, that since its inception was an enemy of Open Source, acquired GitHub - they don't sell (to me) the idea that they are now a different company. They will have to do more to show so. So far they have done nothing compared to what they have arguably taken.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;I have removed all my github projects and will not use it in the future completely due to the acquisition.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;As far as I am concerned this is the end of GitHub.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Cloud data never belongs to the user, but always to the cloud provider.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Many team members are not concerned about the use of Github, and the convenience of the features on Github are useful. Visibility of the project (example Mapserver) is very important to some team leaders, and there is no replacement. We at OSGeo dot org have already built our own git server, and it is popular in our group.. the content of the projects is perfectly mirrored, but the tickets and PR history does not port. Some people have found tools to migrate away from Github, but it has not happened in general. The opinions about this are very divided, with strong feelings on different sides.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;/assets/js/chart/01.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</content><summary type="html">These question are done by all participants.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://ammyblabla.github.io/microsoftGitHub/images/pic02.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Result from Google form (Part 2)</title><link href="https://ammyblabla.github.io/microsoftGitHub/blog/result-google-form-02/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Result from Google form (Part 2)" /><published>2018-07-16T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-07-16T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://ammyblabla.github.io/microsoftGitHub/blog/result-google-form-02</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ammyblabla.github.io/microsoftGitHub/blog/result-google-form-02/">&lt;script src=&quot;https://ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/libs/jquery/3.3.1/jquery.min.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://code.highcharts.com/highcharts.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://code.highcharts.com/modules/exporting.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://code.highcharts.com/modules/export-data.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;/assets/css/table.css&quot; /&gt;

&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;/assets/css/chart.css&quot; /&gt;

&lt;h2 style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;Result from Google form&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The questions of this section ask about perception to GitHub. The participations of this survey are developers who involve in Linux distribution and BSD project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;content&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;chart&quot; id=&quot;3-1&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  
  &lt;div class=&quot;spacer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div id=&quot;table-scroll&quot; class=&quot;3-3&quot;&gt;
    &lt;table&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;I like GitHub but I like GitLab more. The main point is there's more devs on GitHub than on GitLab at least for now&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;FreeBSD doesn't use GitHub as its primary source anyway.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;i do not trust microsoft&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;It's quite hard for me to trust Microsoft, they're probably still planning to EEE stuff - even a &quot;harmless&quot; tiger raised in captivity will still bite.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;The problem is, if too much devs move to other platforms, then the greatest benefit of GitHib (easy cross-contribution and linking between different projects) will be lost. Thus follow the herd ;).&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Microsoft has shown multiple times in the past that they have no problems stealing ideas from open source software. Their ability to change the foundations and the fundamentals of your project by using terms and conditions will result in a poorer product and more people worried about legal implications instead of writing code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It's just better and easier to move to a different system.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Github has strong support for SaaS integration (CI/CD services in particular), but these services are provided by third parties. Github's competitors such as Gitlab and Atlassian Bitbucket provide CI/CD functionality as part of their packages which would probably make me decide to use them instead of Github if I had to set up a new user account right now.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Usability and access to versioning is not userfriendly, and needs to learn commands and knowledge to make the best use of it.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;It's easy to migrate to other git hosting platforms, but that's not needed right now for me.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Their terrible workplace history is far more of an issue than their ownership and competent HR department could only be an improvement.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;A Platform to develop OpenSource software cannot be controlled by King of closed source software. It's a contradiction.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Microsoft support troll companies against Linux. I hate this.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;I’ve never been too fond of GitHub, but I doubt Microsoft would make it any worse. If, at all, they might make it slightly better. I think those moving away in panic to *other* commercial platforms like GitLab are idiots and hypocrites.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Practically speaking, nothing has changed yet. We are not even talking about predictions, but about &quot;gut feelings&quot;.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Github is great for smaller projects but more serious projects need faster services.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Imho GitLab is superior in parts of functionality but is still lacking the userbase.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;GitHub was closed-source either way, Microsoft acquiring it doesn't change much. (Yet.)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Github is great and has done a lot for the free software movement, but there are technically superior alternatives that are free software now, while github is propietary.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;It's useful for mirrors in order to make it easy for drive-by contributors.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;The Debian project had always been in favour of not using services running on infrastructure that is not managed by Debian. Impact to the project has been minimal as we had already our own infrastructure (Alioth recently migrated to salsa.debian.org, our own gitlab infrastructure). Debian is used to handling upstream developers using many different forges (Sourceforge, Savannah, GitHub, Gitlab) and the impact of upstream moving from GitHub to GitSalsa has not been significant.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;i'm preparing to leave github with my personal projects before microsoft takes over control to a personal gitea instance!&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;I think it is too early to say what the impact is and most of the moves away seem to be hysteria rather than rational decisions.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;GitHub was already a proprietary platform, and continues to be a proprietary platform. Its sole advantage is network effects: most users are already on GitHub and used to GitHub.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Microsoft brings money, money means stable and reliable hosting of our source code.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Github has been core to projects I work on, including Chef and Samba. Moving would be awkward: but Microsoft could very easily destroy the trust critical to these projects, much as Sourceforge ruined trust in their repositories by poisoning the idle Windows GIMP project with adware. Trust in Microsoft's business practices is low, for strong historical reason, and it will take a long time to earn that trust.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Gitlab is an great open source alternative to github.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Monocultures are to be avoided, GitHub should simply be one of a number of similar projects to be used by software projects.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;  
    &lt;/table&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;spacer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;chart&quot; id=&quot;4-1&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;spacer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;4-5&quot; id=&quot;table-scroll&quot;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Practically speaking, nothing has changed yet. We are not even talking about predictions, but about &quot;gut feelings&quot;.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;A Platform to develop OpenSource software cannot be controlled by King of closed source software. It's a contradiction.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;It's quite hard for me to trust Microsoft, they're probably still planning to EEE stuff - even a &quot;harmless&quot; tiger raised in captivity will still bite. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Their terrible workplace history is far more of an issue than their ownership and  competent HR department could only be an improvement.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;i'm preparing to leave github with my personal projects before microsoft takes over control to a personal gitea instance!&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Github is great and has done a lot for the free software movement, but there are technically superior alternatives that are free software now, while github is propietary.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;I think it is too early to say what the impact is and most of the moves away seem to be hysteria rather than rational decisions.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;It's useful for mirrors in order to make it easy for drive-by contributors.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Microsoft brings money, money means stable and reliable hosting of our source code.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Github has been core to projects I work on, including Chef and Samba. Moving would be awkward: but Microsoft could very easily destroy the trust critical to these projects, much as Sourceforge ruined trust in their repositories by poisoning the idle Windows GIMP project with adware. Trust in Microsoft's business practices is low, for strong historical reason, and it will take a long time to earn that trust.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Github is great for smaller projects but more serious projects need faster services.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Microsoft support troll companies against Linux. I hate this.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;I’ve never been too fond of GitHub, but I doubt Microsoft would make it any worse. If, at all, they might make it slightly better. I think those moving away in panic to *other* commercial platforms like GitLab are idiots and hypocrites.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;GitHub was already a proprietary platform, and continues to be a proprietary platform. Its sole advantage is network effects: most users are already on GitHub and used to GitHub.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;The Debian project had always been in favour of not using services running on infrastructure that is not managed by Debian. Impact to the project has been minimal as we had already our own infrastructure (Alioth recently migrated to salsa.debian.org, our own gitlab infrastructure). Debian is used to handling upstream developers using many different forges (Sourceforge, Savannah, GitHub, Gitlab) and the impact of upstream moving from GitHub to GitSalsa has not been significant.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Usability and access to versioning is not userfriendly, and needs to learn commands and knowledge to make the best use of it.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;It's easy to migrate to other git hosting platforms, but that's not needed right now for me.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;i do not trust microsoft&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Imho GitLab is superior in parts of functionality but is still lacking the userbase.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;FreeBSD doesn't use GitHub as its primary source anyway.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Gitlab is an great open source alternative to github. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;GitHub was closed-source either way, Microsoft acquiring it doesn't change much. (Yet.)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Monocultures are to be avoided, GitHub should simply be one of a number of similar projects to be used by software projects.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Microsoft has shown multiple times in the past that they have no problems stealing ideas from open source software. Their ability to change the foundations and the fundamentals of your project by using terms and conditions will result in a poorer product and more people worried about legal implications instead of writing code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It's just better and easier to move to a different system. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;I like GitHub but I like GitLab more. The main point is there's more devs on GitHub than on GitLab at least for now&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Github has strong support for SaaS integration (CI/CD services in particular), but these services are provided by third parties. Github's competitors such as Gitlab and Atlassian Bitbucket provide CI/CD functionality as part of their packages which would probably make me decide to use them instead of Github if I had to set up a new user account right now.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;The problem is, if too much devs move to other platforms, then the greatest benefit of GitHib (easy cross-contribution and linking between different projects) will be lost. Thus follow the herd ;).&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;spacer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;chart&quot; id=&quot;5-1&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;spacer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;chart&quot; id=&quot;5-3&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;spacer&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;5-4&quot; id=&quot;table-scroll&quot;&gt;
    &lt;table&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;This has always been a proprietary service using open source technologies. The owner doesn't really matter to me as long as they don't mess with code or visibility of projects for business purposes.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Our distribution have a separate development platform.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Just a casual user. But my biggest issue with github is search has been changed. The change I like is if I'm on some project page. The made it easier to search that project repo or search for a new project on github. But they made a dumb ass decision to penalized you for searching to much. Or hell, make spelling mistakes and try to search again. Nope the site start bitching about you searching too much. It's really starting to piss me off! &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;The problem is NOT GitHUB-Microsoft deal but more general, a small example: in the past we (nearly) all use usenet. There are TONS of newserver around the world, anyone can host another if he or she want. There are plenty of groups some fun, some about sport, some about work, some to help others, some to discuss new ideas, ... today we have FEW non-integrated proprietary platforms (from Fb to StackExchange to Reddit to 4Chan, YC, ... all of them are POOR replacements of ancient ng. All of them are proprietary and depend on a single company.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For GitHub (&amp;amp;co) the situation is the same: in the past (an few project keep this paradigma) we work on ml, we host projects on a variety of hosts, many are from project members itself (think at Debian's mirros by ISPs that use Debian). Now people tend to concentrate on single proprietary platform like GitHub, GitLab etc. It doesn't matter if the holder is Microsoft or Dr. Foo Bar: they are company, their goal is making money. We can have a common interest but it can't least forever. On open platforms when the interest diverge the switch is easy, for instance if you change your mail service it's a matter of IMAP transfert. If you switch from a proprietary platform to another MANY thing may change. It may be hard.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If the use of GitHub is limited as a repository mirror there are little issue, they are substantial &quot;open hosters&quot;, but if you use PR&amp;amp;other GitHub features you are locked-in.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;MS has it now, it's best to stay away.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;People are generally moving to GitLab, which is much nicer.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;suck microsoft&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;As an open source project, we want to use open source tools wherever possible.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Microsoft has proven over and over again that they don't have any ethical limits nor respect legal obligations (if possible) in their attempt to increase profit AND destroy competitors. Monopolies are detrimental to society &amp;amp; economy.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Alternatives (e.g. GitLab) have IMO a better UI and advanced features (e.g. GitLab CI), I hope that due to this purchase more people will move to GitLab (which I'd actually love to work with, even in OSS)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;I will leave some projects on GitHub but am using BitBucket for others.  I am trying to limit the potential damage Microsoft will do.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;MS will impede development of competitive sw to MS products&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;GitHub was largely unusable for me even before the acquisition due to poor SSH/GPG compatibility, so most of my contributions were already diverted to other places. After the Microsoft announcement I decided to delete my account entirely.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;/assets/js/chart/02.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</content><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to send this survey?</title><link href="https://ammyblabla.github.io/microsoftGitHub/blog/how-to-send-survey/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to send this survey?" /><published>2018-07-01T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-07-01T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://ammyblabla.github.io/microsoftGitHub/blog/how-to-send-survey</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ammyblabla.github.io/microsoftGitHub/blog/how-to-send-survey/">&lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot;&gt;
img {
  width : 100%
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sending survey is one of important process. We pay much attention to select the target and channel. We want to make sure this request does not disturb developers working. However, Getting answer is very important too. We would like to get answer from our target, does not just people from somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 3 choices for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-forums&quot;&gt;1. Forums&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/forumsAndMail/forum1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forum is the most open way. Everyone can see this survey request, but we want to make sure our participants are our target. We solve this problem by choosing specific forums. We choose each distribution forums. In these forums, there are contributor and users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should post on the most opened room, off-topic or general room. Specific room may disturb developers because they may use these forum to track user issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-mailing-lists&quot;&gt;2. Mailing Lists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/forumsAndMail/mailing2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mailing lists means send only one mail but receivers are who subscribe mailing lists so there are more than one receivers.
Developers usually use mailing lists to communicate in their work, so it may disturb developers’ working. However mailing lists are better than forums if we want to specify our target. The request of mailing lists should be more personal than forums example for the forums,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Dear contributors,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For mailing list, we change it into..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Dear XXXXX developers,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both forums and mailing lists have “rules”. You have to read it before post or send something. If the rule do not let us to post, you do not post or send. If you violate, you may be banned. It is hard for you to send further survey on the banning forums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-developers-email&quot;&gt;3. Developers’ Email&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/forumsAndMail/email1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is the most specific way to send. In my opinion, if I recieve survey invitation email, I will think it is spam and I will throw it to the trash. However, this is the last choice and we did not send any request via email since we recieve enough reponses from both mailing lists and forums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find developers’ email by their GitHub. You get the developers GitHub username and search them on the Internet. Some of distros reveal their team on their website, and some of distros also reveal email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover there are “contact form”. We do not send via contact form because we do not sure our target receive this request or not. Some of them may be reach because developers monitor this form by themselves, but some of form sales monitor this form and may look over this request.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">If making survey is heart, sending survey is heart too.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://ammyblabla.github.io/microsoftGitHub/images/survey_cover.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to make this survey?</title><link href="https://ammyblabla.github.io/microsoftGitHub/blog/how-to-do-survey/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to make this survey?" /><published>2018-07-01T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2018-07-01T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://ammyblabla.github.io/microsoftGitHub/blog/how-to-do-survey</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ammyblabla.github.io/microsoftGitHub/blog/how-to-do-survey/">&lt;p&gt;Our survey available on this link https://goo.gl/forms/xe8Y1MrvUO83rfKK2&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-reading-news-and-article-about-microsoft-aquisition&quot;&gt;1. reading news and article about Microsoft aquisition.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linuxfoundation.org/blog/microsoft-buys-github-the-linux-foundations-reaction/&quot;&gt;Microsoft Buys GitHub: The Linux Foundation’s Reaction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=14972872&quot;&gt;Why GitHub Can’t Host the Linux Kernel Community&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zdnet.com/article/linux-foundation-microsofts-github-buy-is-a-win-for-open-source/&quot;&gt;Linux Foundation: Microsoft’s GitHub buy is a win for open source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zdnet.com/article/github-rivals-gain-from-microsoft-acquisition-but-its-no-mass-exodus-yet/&quot;&gt;GitHub rivals gain from Microsoft acquisition but it’s no mass exodus, yet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-defining-goal-and-assumption-of-this-survey&quot;&gt;2. defining goal and assumption of this survey.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;goal&quot;&gt;Goal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do contributors of the Linux distributions perceive Microsoft acquirement GitHub?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;assumption&quot;&gt;Assumption&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developers are afraid of change&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developers have personal preferences&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developers prefer the features of GitHub&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developers are more interested in technical aspects
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;target&quot;&gt;Target&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We target contributors of Linux distributions/kernel and BSD families because you are serious developers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-design-question&quot;&gt;3. Design question&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our question have to answer the assumptions and not straightforward. However, it is just draft, we create question straightforward and will revise them later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-answer&quot;&gt;How to answer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We try to make you easy to answer and not scroll anything for answer the questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;multiple-choice&quot;&gt;Multiple choice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/choice/multiple.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want participants to answer only one choice, so I use basic multiple choice. This is the easiest way to answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;checkbox&quot;&gt;Checkbox&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/choice/checkbox.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of participants hestitate to answer these questions, so participants can select more than one answer and can add new choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;linear-scale&quot;&gt;Linear scale&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/choice/linear_scale.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  Most of question use linear scale. Linear scale is easy to answer and interprete. We put “No opinion” at number 0 for hestitate participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;long-answer&quot;&gt;Long answer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/choice/long_answer.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  Participant can feel free to put all of their opinion in this box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-implement-question-on-survey-platform&quot;&gt;4. Implement question on survey platform&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We choose Google form as survey platform because it is all free and easy to contribute. However, there are many people don’t apply this survey because they do not trust Google privacy. As a result, I change to use eSurvey Creator. This tool is free for student.
  Actually, there are many great tools, but they have some limitations which affect with our work such as&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create no more than 10 questions per survey.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Receive no more than 100 response per month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are not enough for this survey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-design-section&quot;&gt;5. Design Section&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good spliting section will make good participant experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;participants-should-not-scroll-while-apply-a-survey&quot;&gt;Participants should not scroll while apply a survey.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;but-dont-split-too-much-section&quot;&gt;but don’t split too much section&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;hide-page-number-or-survey-progress-if-you-use-logic-flow&quot;&gt;Hide page number or survey progress if you use logic flow.&lt;/h3&gt;</content><summary type="html">Making survey is heart of this work.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://ammyblabla.github.io/microsoftGitHub/images/survey_cover.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Massively: The Jekyll Theme!</title><link href="https://ammyblabla.github.io/microsoftGitHub/blog/welcome-to-massively-the-jekyll-theme/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Massively: The Jekyll Theme!" /><published>2017-10-31T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2017-10-31T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://ammyblabla.github.io/microsoftGitHub/blog/welcome-to-massively-the-jekyll-theme</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ammyblabla.github.io/microsoftGitHub/blog/welcome-to-massively-the-jekyll-theme/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-use-this-theme&quot;&gt;How to Use This Theme&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just go ahead and read up on &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;how to install Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. It’s not too hard I promise!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download this repository &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/iwiedenm/jekyll-theme-massively&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and save it to any folder you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open a terminal window or a command line and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; to that location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then enter: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bundle exec jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;. You can now access your new Jekyll site from &lt;a href=&quot;http://127.0.0.1:4000/&quot;&gt;http://127.0.0.1:4000/&lt;/a&gt;. Have fun exploring your new site!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;features&quot;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;auto-generating-sitemap&quot;&gt;Auto-Generating Sitemap&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sitemap is auto generated! Just simply change the front matter of each site. It looks like so…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sitemap:
    priority: 0.7
    lastmod: 2017-11-02
    changefreq: weekly
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;formspring-integration&quot;&gt;Formspring integration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The contact form below each page on the footer actually collects information! Just change your email address in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt; file!&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Huge thanks to HTML5 UP for making this awesome template! Let's see what it can do</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://ammyblabla.github.io/microsoftGitHub/images/pic02.jpg" /></entry></feed>
